Andrii Abramov

Java Software Engineer

Contacts

Phone: +38 (097) 884 70 64

E-mail:

<u>abramov.andrii@gmail.com</u> Skype ID: abramov.andrii LinkedIn: https://ua.linkedin.com/in/andrii-abramov

Github: https://github.com/Abrasha

Personal statement

I am a young and promising software developer. Mostly, I am specialized on JVM-based languages like Java and Groovy. I have more than two years of developing back end as well as client Android applications. I am fond of learning something new, domesticating new technologies and expanding horizons of my knowledge.

Core skills

Programming Languages / Technologies

- Java, Groovy
- Android
- Python
- JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- Bash
- SQL, HQL
- OOD & Design Patterns

Methodologies

- Agile
- SCRUM
- Kanban
- Waterfall

Frameworks

- Spring
- Hibernate
- JUnit
- JDBC
- slf4j, log4j

Application / Web Servers

- Tomcat
- Jetty

RDBMS

- MySQL
- HSQLDB
- SQLite3

Development Tools

- Intellij IDEA
- Android Studio
- Gradle advanced, Maven
- Git, Perforce
- Jenkins, Travis CI
- VirtualBox

Operating Systems

- Linux Mint, Ubuntu
- macOS
- Microsoft Windows

Experience

Software Engineer - Kyiv, Ukraine

(June 2016 - Present)

Developing and maintaining a large-scaled Android secure library. Designing automated test architecture.

Duties

- Developing Android Secure SDK
- Analysing and debugging code
- Automated test coverage
- Bug fixing
- Maintaining continuous integration server (Jenkins)

Software Engineer - Kyiv, Ukraine

(March 2016 - June 2016)

Developing a full stack web application for managing zoo. It was a project in the SoftServe IT academy.

Duties:

- Feature implementing
- Developing REST service
- Developing client web interface using modern technologies

Software Engineer - Kyiv, Ukraine

(September 2015 – January 2016)

I was leading a team-based project where I was collaborating with couple of my group mates. The purpose of project is to make things easier and more organized for students and teachers.

Duties:

- Developing a JavaFX standalone application
- Design an architecture for application
- Perform code review of pull requests
- Support VCS

Education

National Technical University of Ukraine "Kyiv Polytechnic Institute"

Faculty of Applied Mathematics

Bachelor, Graduating in 2018

Certification

Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 8 Programmer